<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Monero Bahçesi</title>
      <link>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Monero Bahçesi</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>3.2 Saved</title>
    <link>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/savings</link>
    <guid>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/savings</guid>
    <description>At first, having more of something than what you needed was an accident. Either by having luck and finding food laying around, managing to kill an animal bigger than expected, or plain stealing it from someone else.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 10:16:05 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>3.3 Is Monero money?</title>
    <link>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/is_this_money</link>
    <guid>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/is_this_money</guid>
    <description>Yes it is. Don’t get lost in philosophic or etymological discussions. If it walks and talks like a duck, it’s probably a duck. If you earned it with your work, and you saved it for a while, and you spend it to buy something else, then it works like money.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 10:16:05 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>3.4 A personal choice</title>
    <link>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/personal_choice</link>
    <guid>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/personal_choice</guid>
    <description>A transaction should be a personal choice. Giving something out should be something an individual decides to do willingly. For that to the true, the individual must have ownership of the thing to be given.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 10:16:05 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>3.5 A fresh start</title>
    <link>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/fresh_start</link>
    <guid>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/fresh_start</guid>
    <description>The internet gave us freedom to explore being someone else. Then, and only willingly, bring that new self back into the real world, updated. A different identity is a tool we can use to change our current one.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 10:16:05 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>3.6 Trying things out</title>
    <link>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/trying_things</link>
    <guid>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/trying_things</guid>
    <description>The first picture that comes to our minds when we think about censorship is censorship by force. An evil Orwellian government sending the police to knock down the doors of those who do not comply with the current speech law, regardless of that law being good or bad.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 10:16:05 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>3.7 Honest opinion</title>
    <link>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/honest_opinion</link>
    <guid>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/honest_opinion</guid>
    <description>In the Asch conformity experiments they put a person in a room together with other seven fake participants. Just like a ring signature, one true mixed up with many decoys Then they show them all a picture with three vertical lines of very obvious different lengths, and ask: ¿What line is equal to the first line, A, B or C? Even though there’s a clear correct answer, if the fake participants answer out loud first, and say A for example, the real participant answering last, will give the same wrong answer a third of the time.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 10:16:05 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>3.8 Wisdom of the crowd</title>
    <link>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/wisdom_of_the_crowd</link>
    <guid>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/wisdom_of_the_crowd</guid>
    <description>In the candy jar experiment, we fill a glass jar with a lot of candies or pebbles or anything that would be difficult to guess the number of by only looking ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 10:16:05 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>3.9 The price of strings</title>
    <link>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/strings_attached</link>
    <guid>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/3-notes-for-humans/strings_attached</guid>
    <description>Giving money to someone should not have strings attached. When you gift with a money that allows you to trace everything the receiver does afterwards (and possible before the fact as well) is a poisoned gift.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 10:16:05 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Hoşgeldin</title>
    <link>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/</link>
    <guid>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/</guid>
    <description>Kendini küçük ve paslı bir demir parmaklı kapıdan geçerken hayal et. Kapı sonuna kadar açık, ve kapıdan geçerken sarı pirinç bir plaka üzerinde Monero Bahçesi yazan bir tabela görüyorsun.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 10:16:05 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2.43 A couple of minutes</title>
    <link>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/2-blueprint-for-geeks/block_time</link>
    <guid>https://k4r4b3y.github.io/monerobahcesi/2-blueprint-for-geeks/block_time</guid>
    <description>We’re designing a system that is decentralized, but one thing that is always difficult to do when we have a group of different people is to coordinate ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 10:16:05 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>